JACK SENECHAL

1901 8th St, Berkeley, CA 94710 415-779-2701 ♦ jacksenechal@gmail.com jacksenechal.com/resume ♦ github.com/jacksenechal

INTRODUCTION

I am an engineer with a passion for the future. I wish to see clean and lucid technology guiding the world's vector of change toward the long-term greatest good of humanity. I have a deep interest in the architecture of complex systems and facilitating emergence. I value foresight, innovation, multidimensional thinking, and appropriate application of technology. I am existentially intolerant of the status quo.

My current professional interests include building tools for community self-organization, including tools for identity, trust, collaboration, annotation, and discovery. I'm fascinated with application and data ecosystems, and would like to see more flexibility and crossover between systems. Other interests include human-computer interaction, appropriate technology, sustainable development, open source everything, mountain biking, snow sports, and meditation.

I bring 10+ years of industry experience. My ideal workplace has a vibrant environment of innovation, a strong team practicing Agile methodologies, and a culture of excellence. It is more than a day job, it is a platform to launch big ideas. I have played many roles over the years, and am open to the right job, whatever form that takes. If you think you have a great position for me, let's discuss.

LANGUAGES AND TECHNOLOGIES

Programming experience with Ruby, Rails, JavaScript, CoffeeScript, Node.js, jQuery, D3, PHP, ActionScript, Flex, and SuperCollider. Limited experience with C/C++, Java, Perl and Python. Deeply familiar with MVC.

Experience with automated testing in JavaScript, Ruby, PHP, Selenium, and ActionScript.

Most comfortable developing with Vim on Linux.

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Arts from the University of North Carolina at Asheville (May, 2003)

- Major in mathematics, minor in computer science
- Undergraduate research in mathematics
- Graduated with distinction in mathematics

OPEN SOURCE PROJECTS

Enlightened Structure 2007 - current

 Co-founded the Enlightened Structure metaproject to facilitate the emergence of an open, decentralized global infrastructure for applications to make use of rich cloud data such as identity, reputation, and commons licensed content, and to lead the way with reference applications such as a forking-based collaboration engine and visualization tools for navigating the global semantic

- graph.
- Research and synthesis of information on candidate technologies
- Code contributions to related projects (primarily written in Ruby and JavaScript)

Skype Links Chrome Extension 2011

• A Chrome extension to make callto: or skype: links out of phone numbers on web pages

INDUSTRY EXPERIENCE

Superluminal Systems AUG 2013 - current

- Helped to develop and launch the first client site based on the Superluminal Learning Management System.
- Collaboration on innovative user interface elements using D3 and CoffeeScript.
- Wordpress plugin wrangling, development and customization.

OpenTest Pro, LLC 2008 - 2011

- Founded the company to provide educational resources relating to automated testing and continuous integration using open source tools in a PHP environment.
- Activities include technical writing, web application development in Ruby on Rails and Flex, studio voiceover recording, and project management.

Independent Contracting 2004 - 2009

- Turnbull & Asser shirtmakers (2008-2009). Built a virtual showroom for their bespoke department, allowing users to browse fabrics and place orders. Ruby on Rails backend, Flash frontend.
- Idance.net video dance instruction (2004-2005). Designed and implemented an e-commerce site in PHP and MySQL. Pay-per-download purchasing, content browsing and searching, back-end for the client to manage the site with detailed admin reports on purchases and user activity.
- Various smaller websites and components.

OnForce, Inc - New York, NY JUNE 2006 - DEC 2007

- Programmed features and updates to the OnForce platform.
- Introduced automated testing with PHPUnit. Implemented tests for OnForce's public-facing API.
 Unit testing infrastructure included PHPUnit with a custom test database refreshing mechanism,
 Selenium, and CruiseControl.
- Integrated OnFoce platform with Salesforce APIs to provide up-to-date customer information for sales and support teams.
- Project managed the implementation of Salesforce throughout the company, and oversaw the administration of the application.

JBA Network - Asheville, NC JUNE 2003 - DEC 2006

- Project manager and lead programmer for medium-scale web application, mynewsletterbuilder.com. Designed the application and coded the initial release. Later oversaw the ongoing development team for the project. MNB remains one of the primary revenue sources for the company.
- Developed a modular, evented, MVC programming framework for PHP.
- Concept development, project management, and programming for other company products and services, including www.jukeboxalive.com and www.byregion.net.
- Systems administration and networking (Linux, Windows).

US Navy FNMOD - Asheville, NC MAY 2001 - AUG 2001

Programmer, database designer for the Fleet Numerical Meteorology and Oceanography
Detachment. Migrated Navy weather data from a flat text format to a MySQL database. Wrote a
Java application for quality checking weather data, and converting it to a MySQL-accessible
format.

Freelance - Sydney, Australia DEC 1999 - DEC 2000

• Web designer, programmer. Developed a Java search engine applet for a CD-ROM based knowledge bank. Various other web development and graphic design projects.

Internet Safety Association - Asheville, NC DEC 1998 - DEC 1999

• Designer, computer technician. HTML and JavaScript programming, graphic design, web design and management, network management, computer repairs and upgrades.

Various - Asheville, NC 1996 - 1998

 Assorted computer related jobs and volunteer work, including CAT-5 and fiber-optic network installation, web development, desktop publishing, technical writing, computer repair, and technical support.

Excellent References Available Upon Request